# RYAN GROESCH

## **Software Developer**

Seattle, WA (206) 295-1320 ryan.groesch@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ryan-groesch github.com/ryan-g13

Full-stack JavaScript developer with a background in technology and customer service. 4 years of experience as a technical account manager working in an Agile environment. Customer oriented and data driven approach to solving problems with programming.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Washington**, Seattle, WA Bachelor of Science – Physics

Code Fellows, June 2018

Certificate - Advanced Software Development in Full-Stack JavaScript

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, Python, SQL/SQLITE/PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3.

Tools: React, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, Page.js, jQuery, MongoDB, GitHub, Heroku, Jest, Artillery.io.

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Jira, TDD, SASS, SMACCSS, RESTful APIs, SDLC.

Operating Systems: OS X, Windows, Linux.

### **PROJECTS**

EventUs, June 2018 - https://github.com/EventUs-CF

- Full-stack (MERN) social media platform which is geo-localized around the user and alleviates the
  need to post to multiple social media platforms. EventUs provides a streamlined UI for events near
  the user and persists the organized data in an efficient manner.
- JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB (Mongoose), Jest, Enzyme, Artillery.io.

#### PubHub, May 2018 - https://github.com/Pub-Hub/401-Project

- Backend application to generate pub crawls, utilizes user authentication, persistence via MongoDB, route optimization with GraphHopper API and text message integration with Twilio API.
- JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB (Mongoose), Jest, Artillery.io.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Design Imports, September 2017 - November 2017 | Product Manager

- Designed ad campaigns on the Amazon platform to maximize exposure and ROI.
- Utilized headline search, product display, sponsored ads, A+ content and hidden search terms to improve click-through rate (CTR).
- Created and managed online catalog of over 1000 products, including familial grouping of products.

## Amazon, June 2016 - May 2017 | Technical Account Manager - Kindle Content Operations

- Ran weekly audits and coached team to reduce errors below desired metrics (identified trends and keywords to optimize algorithm).
- Created and adapted weekly and monthly metrics reports, using SQL, including expansion to global level (Multi-marketplace).
- Identified and executed high impact projects leading to global performance improvements (TitleSet linking project).
- Worked across teams (VM, BI/BA and Publishers) to get content online (ran meetings and assigned top targeted titles to VMs).
- Created and updated SOP documents for above processes.

## Amazon, Oct 2014 - Sept 2015 | Technical Account Manager - Digital Video Games and Software

- Worked as Quality Assurance Liaison to run manual user testing of the globally launched Developer Portal V2.
- Tested and verified products that passed the Amazon Quality Assurance criteria and rating system.
- Systematically kept records of productivity and detailed notes on problem products.
- Designed and edited product pages in HTML.

## Amazon, August 2013 - July 2014 Investigation Specialist - Fulfilled By Amazon

- Used the internal Amazon trouble ticketing system to triage and resolve inbound logistical issues between Sellers and Fulfillment Centers.
- Identified fraudulent patterns and products within the pipeline to be quarantined and deep dived the root cause.
- Helped to redesign the training documents that decreased the on-boarding time from 4 weeks to 2 weeks.

# Google Maps, May 2012 - August 2013 | Visual Data Specialist

- Fixed user reported GIS (geographic information system) and directional issues regarding functionality of Google Maps.
- Developed policies and rules regarding new use cases for "High Priority" team (team that managed highest priority routes such as highways).
- Worked on the "High Priority" team handling sensitive data and research-intensive issues.